Guide to the Peabody Museum of Natural History, Yale University, Botanical Teaching Slides
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Peabody Museum of Natural History, Yale University, botanical teaching slides
1900-1940
RU 93
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
62.5
(125 boxes)
The materials consist of lantern slides maintained by the Peabody Museum of Natural History at Yale University documenting North American vegetation and habitats.
Peabody Museum of Natural History
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 33-A (YRG 33-A), Records of the Peabody Museum.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of lantern slides maintained by the Peabody Museum of Natural History at Yale University documenting North American vegetation and habitats.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged alphabetically by specimen or geographic location.
Botany; Lantern slides; Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Glass Slides, Accession 1989-A-042
  Scope and Contents
  Note: number in the folder column refers to slide code number.
  - Abies
    - Fir Forest (Abies)
      General note
      See: Spruce
    - Abies amabilis (Box 1, Folder D1A)
    - Abies balsamea (Box 1)
    - Abies concolor (Box 1, Folder D35A)
    - Abies fraseri
      - North Carolina Mts. (Box 2, Folder D36A)
    - Abies grandis (Box 2)
    - Abies lasiocarpa
      See: Mt. Rainier Travel Series
    - Abies magnifica
      See: Abies concolor (Sargent's Silva) No. D23A
    - Abies nobilis. Photo. H.S. Graves, 1896 (Box 3, Folder D73A)
    - Abies venusta. Santa Lucia Mts., Califoria (Box 3)
  - Acer
    - Acer baratum (Box 3)
    - Acer glabrum (Box 3)
    - Acer macrophyllum (Box 3)
    - Acer negundo (Box 3)
    - Acer pennsylvanicum
      See: Tsuga-Hemlock and A. penn., No. D15Y, D22Y See: Acer spicatum, No. D62B
      - Huron Mts., north Michigan (Box 3)
    - Acer platanoides (Box 3, Folder D7B)
    - Acer pseudoplatanus (Box 4, Folder D8B)
    - Acer rubrum (Box 4)
    - Acer saccharinum (Box 4)
    - Acer saccharum, 1933 (Box 4, Folder D49B)
      See: Evonymuus-Leaf arrangement, No. D10F
      - Buds-See Acer rubrum buds, No. D11B
    - Acer saccharum, 1931 October (Box 5, Folder D50B)
    - Acer spicatum (Box 5)
  - Aesculus
    - Aesculus glabra
      See: Carya-size of buds
    - Aesculus hippocastanum (Box 5)
    - Aesculus octandra (Box 5)
  - Ailanthus
    See: Rhus glabra-buds, No. D38V
    - Ailanthus glandulosus (Box 5)
      See Tilia-fruits, No. D29X
  - Alnus
    - Alnus glutinosa (Box 6, Folder D91B)
    - Alnus incana (Box 6)
    - Alnus rubra
      - Habitat (young trees)
        See: Chamaecyparis lawsoniana No. D13E
    - Alnus rugosa (Box 6)
    - Alnus oregona (lacking) (Box 6)
  - Amelanchier
    - Amelanchier canadensis
      See: Crataegus coccinea (Sergent's Silva) No. D74E
    - Amelanchier laevis: Brookfield, CT (Box 6)
  - Aralea: Aralea spinosa (Box 6)
  - Arctostaphylos
    - Arctostaphylos glauca (Box 6)
    - Arctostaphylos tomentosa (Box 6)
  - Arbutus
    - Arbutus arizonica: Santa Catal. Mts., Ariz. (Box 6)
    - Arbutus menziesii (Box 6, Folder D21C)
  - Aronia
    - Buds-False Slides
      See: Amelanchier No. D8C
  - Asimina: Asimina triloba (Box 7, Folder A22C)
  - Avicennia: Avicennia nitida (Box 7)
  - Benzoin: Benzoin astivale (Box 7)
  - Berberis
    - Berberis thuubergeii FS
      See: Berberis vulgaris No. D27C
  - Betula
    - Betula alba (Box 7)
    - Betula fontinalis (Box 7)
    - Betula lenta
      See:Betula lutea No. D52C
      See: Alnus No. D92B
    - Betula lutea (Box 7, Folder D56C)
      See: Betula paprifera No. D61C
    - Betula nigra (Box 8, Folder D57C)
    - Betula paprifera
      - Twin Lakes, Conn., 1905 (Box 8)
      - Colebrook, Conn., 1928 (Box 8)
      - Near Burt Lake, Mich., 1911, 1933 (Box 8)
    - Betula populifolia
      See: Alnus No. D97B
      See: Ostrya No. D57J
  - Bigelovia: Bigelovia arborescens (Box 8)
  - Carico (Paw Paw) (lacking)
  - Carpinus: Carpinus caroliniana (Box 8)
  - Carya
    - Carya alba (Box 8, Folder D96C)
      See also: Carya cordiformis No. D2D
    - Carya alba (cont'd) (Box 9, Folder D97C)
    - Carya cordiformis (Box 9)
    - Carya glabra
      See: Carya alba No. D95C
      See: Carya cordiformis No. D2D
    - Carya laciniosa (Box 9)
    - Carya ovata
      See: Carya alba Nos. D95C, D68B
    - Carya pecan (Box 9)
      See: Tillis No. D29X
  - Castanea
    See: Evonymuus No. D10F
    See: Castanea dentata No. D34D
    - Castanea dentata
      - Virginia, 1914 (Box 9, Folder D42D)
      - North Haven, Conn., 1916 (Box 10, Folder D43D)
      - Virginia, 1914 (Box 10)
      - Griswald, Conn., 1918 (Box 10)
      - Washington, Conn., 1919 (Box 10)
      - Sinsbury, Conn., 1918 (Box 10)
      - So. Ontario, 1933 (Box 10)
  - Castanopsis: Castanopsis chysophy (Box 10)
  - Catalpa
    See: Euonymuus No. D10F
    See: Gledesia No. D87F
    - Catalpa speciosa (Box 10)
  - Ceanothera (Box 10)
  - Celastrus
    - Celastrus scandens (Box 10, Folder D79D)
  - Celtis
    - Celtis occidentalis
      See: Morus rubra No. D30J
      - Three Oaks, Mich., 1933 (Box 11, Folder D80D)
  - Cephalanthus: Cephalanthus occidentalis (Box 11)
  - Cercis: Ceris Canadensis (Box 11)
  - Chamaecyparis
    - Chamaecyparis lawsoniana (Box 11, Folder D15E)
    - Chamaecyparis lawsoniana (cont'd) (Box 12, Folder D16E)
    - Chamaecyparis nootkatensia (Box 12)
    - Chamaecyparis thyoides. N.J. pine barrens, 1932 (Box 12)
  - Cladrastis: Cladrastis lutea (Box 12)
  - Clethra
    See: Spirea No. D47W
    See: Syonia No. D12J
  - Cornus (Box 12)
    Slides No. D39E - D47E are missing
  - Cornus
    - Cheshire, Conn., 1931 November (Box 13, Folder D48E)
    - Cornus florida
      - Photo by Rhodes (Box 13)
      - Decker, Ind., 1911 (Box 13)
      - Wahington D.C. WHS, 1933 (Box 13)
      - Edgewood Park, 1931 October (Box 13)
    - Cornus nuttallii (Box 13)
  - Corylus
    - Corylus Americana
      See: Alnus rugosa No. D97B
  - Crataegus
    - Crataegus coccinea (Box 13)
    - Crataegus crus galli (Box 13)
  - Cupressus
    - Cupressus arizonica (Box 13)
    - Cupressus goveniana (Box 13)
    - Cupressus macnabiana (Box 13, Folder D81E)
  - Cupressus
    - Cupressus macrocarpa: Point Lobos, Calif. (Box 14, Folder D82E)
    - Cupressus sargenti: Mt. Tamalpais, Calif. (Box 14)
  - Diospyros
    - Diospyros virginiana, 1932 November (Box 14)
  - Divca (Box 14)
  - Euonymuus: Euonymuus alatus (Box 14)
  - Fagus (Box 14, Folder D20F)
  - Fagus
    - Three Oaks, Mich., 1933 (Box 15, Folder D21F)
    - Fagus Americana (Box 15)
    - Fagus grandifolia (Box 15)
  - Ficus (Box 15, Folder D53F)
  - Fraxinus
    - Fraxinus americana: near Samusville, Va., 1932 (Box 16, Folder D54F)
    - Fraxinus nigra: Three Oaks, Mich., 1911 (Box 16)
    - Fraxinus lanceolata (Box 16)
    - Fraxinus pennsylvanica (Box 16)
  - Galix (Box 16)
  - Gaylussacia (Box 16)
  - Gingko
    - Gingko biloba (Box 16, Folder D86F)
  - Gleditsia: Gleditsia triacanthos (Box 17, Folder D87F)
  - Gymnocladus
    See: Gleditsia No. D87F
    - Gymnoclaudus dioicus (Box 17)
  - Hamamelis
    See: Tilia No. D29X
  - Hicoria
    - Hicoria alba (lacking) (Box 17)
    - Hicoria glabra (Box 17)
    - Hicoria ovata (Box 17)
  - Ilex
    - Ilex opaca: Virginia, ESS, 1932 (Box 17)
    - Ilex verticillata (Box 17, Folder D27G)
      See also: Aesculus glabra No. D68B
      See also: Carya No. D20D
  - Juglaus
    - Juglaus cinerea (Box 18, Folder D28G)
    - Juglaus nigra
      - Pisgah, North Carolina, ESS, 1923 (Box 18)
      - Three Oaks, Mich., 1933 (Box 18)
  - Juniperus
    - So. Nevada-Las Vegas (Box 18)
    - Juniper communis (Box 18, Folder D54G)
  - Juniperus
    - Juniperus occidentalis (Box 19, Folder D55G)
    - Juniperus pachyphloca (Box 19)
    - Juniperus scopulorum (Box 19)
    - Juniperus utahensis (Box 19)
    - Juniperus virginiana
      - North Carolina, 1901 (Box 19, Folder D88G)
      - WRM, 1928 (Box 19)
      - 1932 (Box 19)
      - North Haven, 1932, 1901, 1916 (Box 20, Folder D89G)
      - Montowese, 1932 (Box 20)
      - No. Branford, 1928, 1932 (Box 20)
      - Bethany, 1912 (Box 20)
    - Juniperus (miscellaneous) (Box 20)
  - Kalmia
    - Kalmia latifolia
      - Photo by Rhodes (Box 20)
  - Larix
    - Larix Americana (Box 20)
    - Larix laricina (Box 20, Folder D25H)
    - Larix lyallii (Box 21, Folder D26H)
    - Larix occidentalis: near Missoula, Mont., 1927 (Box 21)
  - Libocedrus: Libocedrus decurrens. Photo by Glock (Box 21)
  - Liquidambar
    - Liquidambar styraciflua
      - Brooksville, Miss. WRM, 1927 (Box 21, Folder D60H)
      - Sumter Co., S.C. WRM, 1926 (Box 21)
      - MMH, 1932 (Box 21)
    - Liquidambar styraciflua (Box 22, Folder D61H)
  - Liriodendron
    - Maryland, LK, 1932 (Box 22)
    - North Carolina, 1915 (Box 22, Folder D98H)
    - Three Oaks, Mich., 1933 (Box 22)
  - Liriodendron
    - Ironton, Ohio JTA, 1930 (Box 23, Folder D99H)
    - Parke Co., Indiana, 1917 (Box 23)
  - Lithocarpus: Lithocarpus densiflora (Box 23)
  - Lyonia
    See: Spiraea No. D47W
  - Magnolia
    - Magnolia acuminata: Tenn. TEO, 1901 (Box 23)
    - Magnolia grandiflora (Box 23)
    - Magnolia tripetala (Box 23)
  - Malus (Box 23)
  - Morus
    - Morus alba (Box 23)
    - Morus rubra (Box 23, Folder D33J)
  - Myrica (Box 23)
    See: Carya No. D20D
    See: Aesculus glabra No. D68B
    - Myrica asplenifolia (Box 24, Folder D34J)
    - Myrica carol.
      See: alnus oregona No. D2C
  - Nyssa
    - Nyssa aquatica (Box 24)
    - Nyssa sylvatica
      See: Cornus alternifolia
  - Ostrya
    See: Carpinus No. D89C
    - Ostrya virginiana (Box 24)
  - Palmae
    - Cocos nucifera (Coconut Palm) (Box 24)
    - Phoenix dactylifera (Date Palm) (Box 24, Folder D64J)
    - Roystonea regia (Royal Palm) (Box 25, Folder D65J)
    - Sabal palmetto (Cabbage Palm): near Sliver Springs, Fla., 1922 (Box 25)
    - Sabal texana (Palmetto) (Box 25)
    - Washingtonia filamentosa (Fan Palm) (Box 25)
  - Picea (Box 25, Folder D92J)
    See also: Hemlock No. D45Y
    - Picea abies (Box 26, Folder D93J)
    - Picea breweriana (Box 26)
    - Picea Canadensis (Box 26, Folder D30K)
      See also: Abies balsamea No. D9A
    - Picea engelmannii (Box 27, Folder D31K)
    - Picea glauca (Box 27, Folder D70K)
    - Picea glauca (cont'd) (Box 28, Folder D71K)
    - Picea mariana (Box 28, Folder D7L)
    - Picea pungens (Box 29, Folder D8L)
    - Picea rubra (Box 29)
    - Picea sitchensis (Box 29, Folder D49L)
      See also: Populus No. D73R
  - Pinus
    - Nichols, 1935 (Box 30, Folder D50L)
    - Pinus albicaulis
      - Cass Lake, Minn. AG, 1903 (Box 30)
      - Idaho KDS, 1936 (Box 30)
      - Huron National Forest, Mich. ESS, 1929 (Box 30)
      - Arapaho, Col. ESS, 1927 (Box 30)
    - Pinus aristata (Box 30)
    - Pinus arizonica (Box 30, Folder D91L)
    - Pinus attenuate (Box 31, Folder D92L)
    - Pinus balfouriana (Box 31)
    - Pinus banksiana
      See: Populus tremuloides No. D71R
      See: Aspen No. D71R
      - Minnesota National Forest, 1916 (Box 31)
    - Pinus caribaea: No. Florida, 1936 (Box 31, Folder D31M)
    - Pinus clausa: Florida (Box 32, Folder D32M)
    - Pinus contorta: Photo by Glock (Box 32)
    - Pinus coulteri (Box 32)
    - Pinus echinata
      - Rhodes (Box 32, Folder D64M)
      - Virginia, WRM, 1929 (Box 32)
    - Pinus echinata (cont'd) (Box 33, Folder D65M)
    - Pinus edulis (Box 33)
    - Pinus flexilis
      - Montana, KDS, 1936 (Box 33)
      - Long's Peak, Colorado (Box 33)
    - Pinus glabra (Box 33)
    - Pinus jeffreyi (Box 33, Folder D3N)
    - Pinus lambertiana: FED, 1935 (Box 34, Folder D4N)
    - Pinus monophylla (Box 34)
    - Pinus montana (Box 34)
    - Pinus monticola: Priest River, Idaho (Box 34, Folder D39N)
    - Pinus muricata: Pike, Colorado ESS, 1927 (Box 35, Folder D40N)
    - Pinus murrayana: Yellowstone National Park (Box 35)
    - Pinus palustris: PSC, 1935 (Box 35, Folder D75N)
    - Pinus palustris (Box 36, Folder D77N)
    - Pinus parryana (Box 36)
    - Pinus ponderosa (Box 36, Folder D140)
    - Pinus ponderosa (Box 37, Folder D150)
    - Pinus pungens (Box 37, Folder D580)
    - Pinus radiate (Box 38, Folder D590)
    - Pinus resinosa
      - Michigan, 1932 (Box 38, Folder D940)
      - No. Minnesota, 1913 (Box 39, Folder D950)
      - 1932 Nov (Box 39)
      - No. Minnesota, 1928 (Box 39)
      - Minnesota National Forest, 1916 (Box 39)
    - Pinus rigida
      - Wharton Brook, 1932 (Box 39, Folder D35P)
      - Wharton Brook, 1921 (Box 39)
      - Wharton Brook, 1932 (Box 39)
      - North Haven, 1916 (Box 39)
    - Pinus rigida (cont'd) (Box 40, Folder D36P)
    - Pinus sabiniana (Box 40)
    - Pinus serotina (Box 40)
    - Pinus strobes
      - Idaho, 1936 (Box 40, Folder D74P)
      - Michigan, 1910 (Box 40)
      - Michigan, 1932 (Box 40)
    - Pinus strobus
      - Huron Mts. Michigan, 1934 (Box 41, Folder D75P-D20Q)
      - Cornwall, Conn., 1932, 1911 (Box 41)
      - Colebrook, Conn., 1912 (Box 41)
      - New Hampshire, 1930, 1929 (Box 41)
      - Vermont, 1931 (Box 42, Folder D21Q)
      - Avon Conn., 1931 (Box 42)
    - Pinus strobiformis (Box 42)
    - Pinus taeda: Auburn, Alabama WRM, 1930 (Box 42, Folder D62Q)
    - Pinus taeda
      - North Carolina, 1901 (Box 43, Folder D63Q)
      - Colebrook, Conn., 1912, 1933, 1932, 1928, 1918 (Box 43)
      - Newton, Colorado, 1928 (Box 43)
    - Pinus torreyana (Box 43, Folder D2R)
    - Pinus virginiana (Box 44, Folder D3R)
  - Planera
    - Planera aquatica
      See: Celtis occidentalis No. D18D
  - Platanus
    - Platanus occidentalis (Box 44)
  - Populus
    - Populus alba (Box 44)
    - Populus balsamifera
      See: Picea No. D74J
    - Populus deltoids (Box 45, Folder D50R)
    - Populus grandidentata (Box 45)
    - Populus nigra (Box 45)
    - Populus tremuloides: Michigan, 1932 (Box 45, Folder D88R)
    - Populus tricocarpa (Box 46, Folder D89R)
  - Prunus
    - Prunus Americana (Box 46)
    - Prunus avium (Box 46)
    - Prunus caroliniana (Box 46)
    - Prunus cerasus (Box 46)
    - Prunus nigra (Box 46)
    - Prunus pennsylvanica (Box 46)
    - Prunus persica (Box 46)
    - Prunus pumila
      See: Betula paprifera No. D68C
    - Prunus serotina: Three Oaks, Michigan, 1933 (Box 46)
    - Prunus virginiana (Box 46)
    - Prunus vireus (Box 46, Folder D26S)
  - Psedera (Box 46)
    - Psedera teudrils (Box 47, Folder D27S)
      See also: Smilax No. D43W
  - Pseudotsuga
    See: Thuja No. D1X
    See: Thuja No. D99W
    - Pseudotsuga macrocarpa (Box 47)
    - Pseudotsuga taxifolis (Box 47, Folder D70S)
    - Pseudotsuga taxifolis (cont'd) (Box 48, Folder D71S)
  - Ptelea
  - Pyrus
    - Pyrus Americana (Box 48)
    - Pyrus communis (Box 48)
    - Pyrus malus (Box 48)
  - Quercus (Box 48, Folder D14T)
  - Quercus (cont'd)
    - Quercus agrifolia (Box 49, Folder D15T)
    - Quercus alba: Orange, Conn., 1932 (Box 49, Folder D54T)
    - Quercus alba
      - Putnam Co., Tenn. AFB, 1907 (Box 50, Folder D55T)
      - Kaniksu, Idaho KDS, 1932 (Box 50)
      - West Virginia ESS, 1935 (Box 50)
      - East Rock, 1931 (Box 50)
    - Quercus bicolor (Box 50)
    - Quercus borealis (Box 50, Folder D97T)
    - Quercus coccinea/ New Haven, 1931 (Box 51, Folder D98T)
    - Quercus chrysolepis (Box 51)
    - Quercus durata (Box 51)
    - Quercus emoryi (Box 51)
    - Quercus garryana (Box 51)
    - Quercus ilicifolia (Box 51)
    - Quercus imbricaria (Box 51)
    - Quercus kelloggii (Box 51)
    - Quercus lobata (Box 51)
    - Quercus macrocarpa: Winona Ranger Dist., Mo. WHS, 1937 (Box 51)
    - Quercus marilandica (Box 51)
    - Quercus michauxii (Box 51, Folder D33U)
    - Quercus montana (Box 52, Folder D34U)
    - Quercus muchlenbergii (Box 52)
    - Quercus myrtifolia: Williamsburg, Va., 1938 (Box 52)
    - Quercus nuttallii (Box 52)
    - Quercus oblongifolia (Box 52)
    - Quercus palustris (Box 52)
    - Quercus prinoides (Box 52)
    - Quercus prinus (Box 52)
    - Quercus rubra (Box 52)
    - Quercus shumardii (Box 52, Folder D71U)
    - Quercus stellata (Box 53, Folder D72U)
    - Quercus texana (Box 53)
    - Quercus velutina (Box 53)
    - Quercus virginiana (Box 53)
  - Rhizophora: Florida, 1936 (Box 53, Folder D15V)
  - Rhododendron
    See: Abies Fraseri-N. Carolina Mts. Nos. D36A and D37A
  - Rhus
    - Rhus diversiloba (Box 54, Folder D16V)
    - Rhus glabra (Box 54)
    - Rhus hirta (Box 54)
    - Rhus toxicodendron (Box 54)
    - Rhus typhina (Box 54)
    - Rhus vernix (Box 54)
  - RIBES (Box 54)
  - Robina
    See: Gldeditsia No. D87F
    See: Zanthoxylon No. D13Z
  - Rosa (Box 55, Folder D62V)
  - Rubus (Box 55)
  - Salix (Box 55)
  - Sassafras (Box 55)
  - Sambucus (Box 55)
  - Sequoia
    - Sequoia gigantea (Box 55, Folder D97V)
    - Sequoia gigantea (Box 56, Folder D98V)
    - Sequoia sempervirens (Box 56)
  - Smilax (Box 56, Folder D43W)
  - Sorbus (Box 57, Folder D44W)
  - Spiraea
    See: Lyonia No. D12J
  - Syringa (Box 57)
  - Symphoricarpus (Box 57)
  - Talus (Box 57)
  - Taxodium
    - Taxodium alscendens (Box 57)
    - Taxodium dictichum (Box 57, Folder D84W)
    - Taxodium imbricarium (Box 58, Folder D85W)
  - Taxus
    - Taxus brevifolia
      See: Tumion Califoricum No. D60Y
  - Toxylon (Box 58)
  - Thuja
    - Thuja occidentalis
      See: Douglas Fir No. D31S
    - Thuja plicata (Box 58, Folder D28X)
  - Tilia (lacking)
    - Tilia americana (Box 59, Folder D29X)
    - Tilia glabra (Box 59)
  - Torreya: Torreya califorica (Box 59)
  - Tsuga
    - Lake Saltonstall, 1911 (Box 59, Folder D67X)
      See also: Larix and Picea glauca No. D8H
    - West Rock, 1939 (Box 60, Folder D68X - D19Y)
    - Colebrook, Conn., 1912, 1928 (Box 60)
    - Sawyer, Mich., 1911 (Box 60)
    - Tsuga Canadensis (Box 61, Folder D20Y)
    - Tsuga carolinensis (Box 61)
    - Tsuga heterophylla
      See: Pseudotsuga No. D52S
      See: Picea sitchensis No. D42L
    - Tsuga mertensiana
      - Washington, EL, 1935 (Box 61)
      - Washington, THG, 1924 (Box 61)
  - Tumion (Box 61)
  - Tupelo (Box 62, Folder D61Y)
  - Ulmus
    - Ulmus Americana: Three Oaks, Mich., 1911 (Box 62)
    - Ulmus fulva (Box 62)
    - Ulmus racemosa (Box 62)
  - Umbellaria (Box 62, Folder D97Y)
  - Vaccinium (Box 63, Folder D98Y)
  - Viburnum
    - Viburnum acerifolium (Box 63)
    - Viburnum alnifolium
      See: Aesculus glabra No. D69B
      See: Aesculus glabra No. D70B
    - Viburnum lentago (Box 63)
    - Viburnum opulus americanum (Box 63)
    - Viburnum prunifolium (Box 63)
  - Vitis
    See: Smilax No. D43W
  - Yucca
    See: Ecology File Yucca under desert
  - Zanthoxylon:, 1931 November (Box 63)
  - Diagrams (Box 63)
  - Maps: Nichols, 1935 (Box 63, Folder D29Z)
  - Travel Series
    - (A) Alaska
      - Glacier Bay, 1916-1935 (Box 64, Folder A1A - A56A)
      - Harriman Expedition (Box 64)
    - (Ac) Arctic: Canadian Arctic Expedition (Box 65, Folder Ac1A - Ac15A)
    - (C) Canada (Box 65, Folder C1A - C11A)
    - (CB) Cape Breton Islands (Box 67, Box 68, Box 66, Box 65, Folder CB1A - CB51B, Box 69)
    - (Co) Colorado (Box 69, Folder Co1A - Co36A)
    - (F) Florida (Box 70, Folder F1A - F44A)
    - (F) Florida (Box 71, Folder F45A - F80A)
    - (GC) Grand Canyon (Box 71, Folder GC1A - GC12A)
    - (G) Guatemala (Box 72, Folder G1A - G22A)
    - (M) Michigan: (Box 72)
      - Isle Royale, 1926, 1909, 1932 (Box 72, Folder M1A - M22A)
      - Isle Royale, 1932, 1909 (Box 73, Folder M23A - M57A)
      - No. Michigan (Box 73)
      - Upper Michigan (Box 73)
      - Upper Michigan, 1925, 1921, 1934 (Box 73)
    - (MI) Minnesota: Air pictures (Box 73, Folder MI1A - MI7A)
    - (MR) Mount Rainier (Box 74, Folder MR1A - MR40A)
    - (MR) Mount Rainier (Box 75, Folder MR41A - MR86A)
    - (N) Nevada: So. Nevada (Las Vegas) (Box 76, Folder N1A - N9A)
    - (NM) New Mexico: New Mexico Mts. (Box 76, Folder NM1A - NM8A)
    - (P) Porto Rico (Box 76, Folder P1A - P2A)
    - (SH) Southern Highlands
      - Blue Ridge Mts. (Box 76, Folder SH1A - SH23A)
      - Cumberland Mts. (Kentucky) (Box 76)
      - Lynn Fork Forest (Kentucky) (Box 76)
    - (SH) Southern Highlands: Reelfoot Lake (Tennessee) (Box 77, Folder SH24A - SH32A)
    - (MW) Mount Washington and Environs: White Mts., 1928 (Box 77, Folder MW1A - MW30A)
    - (MW) Mount Washington and Environs: White Mts., 1928 (Box 78, Folder MW31A - MW43A)
    - (Y) Yellowstone (Box 78, Folder Y1A - Y3A)
    - (Yo) Yosemite (Box 78, Folder Yo1A - Yo11A)
    - (U) Utah (Box 78, Folder U1A)
  - Wild Flowers
    - A (Box 79, Folder B1A - B27A)
      See also: Mt. Rainier No. MR22, MR34
    - B (Box 79, Folder B28A - B31A)
    - C
      See: Mt. Rainier No. MR13
      - Bethany, 1934 (Box 79, Folder B32A - B60A)
      - 1938 (Box 80, Folder B61 - B67A)
    - D (Box 80, Folder B69A - B80A)
    - E, 1906, 1932 (Box 80, Folder B82A - B93A)
      See: Mt. Rainier Nos. MR23, MR24, MR25
    - F (Box 80, Folder B94A)
      See Mt. Rainier No. MR35
    - G (Box 80, Folder B95A - B3B)
    - H: North Haven, 1916 (Box 80, Folder B4B - B8B)
    - I: Shores of Lake Michigan, 1927 (Box 81, Folder B9B - B11B)
    - J (Box 81, Folder B12B)
    - L, 1938 (Box 81, Folder B13B - B27B)
    - M (Box 81, Folder B30B - B34B)
      See: Mt. Rainier No. MR33
    - N (Box 81, Folder B38B - B39B)
    - O (Box 81, Folder B40B - B43B)
    - P (Box 81, Folder B73B - B92B)
      See: Mt. Rainier No. MR27
    - R (Box 82, Folder B95B - B1C)
    - S (Box 82, Folder B2C - B28C)
      See: Mt. Rainier No. MR31
    - T (Box 82, Folder B33C - B39C)
    - U (Box 82, Folder B40C - B41C)
    - V (Box 82, Folder B43C - B48C)
      See: Mt. Rainier No. MR32
      See: Mt. Rainier No. MR14
    - V (Box 83, Folder B48C - B54C)
    - Insectivorous Plants (Box 83)
    - Xerophytes (Box 83)
    - Hydrophytes (Box 83)
  - Ecology of Connecticut
    - A - Plant Succession
      - A-1 Succession on Rock
        - Cornwall, 1931 October (Box 84)
        - West Rock, 1932, 1916 (Box 84)
        - Lantern Hill, 1932, 1911 (Box 84)
        - Mansfield Grove, 1932 (Box 84)
      - A-2 Succession on Sand
        - Wallingford Sand Plains, 1916, 1932 (Box 84)
        - Wharton Brook Sand Plains, 1921, 1932 (Box 84)
      - A-2 Succession on Sand
        - No. Haven Sand Plains, 1901, 1911, 1912, 1915, 1916, 1931, 1932, 1933 (Box 85)
        - Dunes (Box 86)
        - South End beach and dunes, 1911, 1932 (Box 86)
      - A-3 Succession on River Bars, Flood Plains, Lake Shores, Quarry Holes, etc.
        - Muddy River Oxbow pond, 1911, 1932 (Box 86)
      - A-4 Succession on Bogs (Box 87)
      - A-5 Succession on Tidal Flats, Coast Marshes, etc.
        - Salt Marsh (Box 87)
        - Westbrook Salt marsh, 1931 (Box 87)
        - Short Beach, 1932 (Box 87)
        - Quinnipiac River, 1912 (Box 87)
    - B - Invasion (Box 87)
    - C - Temperature Influence (lacking) (Box 87)
    - D - Forest Climax
      - Yale Preserve (E73N, E74N) (Box 88)
      - Marvel Woods, 1908 (Box 88)
      - Cornwall, 1931 (Box 88)
      - Colebrook, 1928 (Box 88)
  - I. Methods
    See: Dendrology File, D76C
    - A - Quadrat
      - Weaver Quadrat, 1916, 1917, 1918 (Box 88)
      - Keene Quadrat, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1928, 1930, 1932 (Box 88)
    - B - The Burn
      - New Zealand, 1898, 1931 (Box 89)
      - Isle Royale, 1927 (Box 89)
    - C - Experimental Vegetation
      - Mycorrhizae (Box 89)
      - N-S Slope (Box 89)
  - II. Principles
    - A - Association (lacking) (Box 89)
    - B - Community (Box 89)
    - C - Plant Succession
      See: Dendrology File, D1K
      See: Dendrology File, D11H
      - 1 - Hydrosere
        - Burt Lake, 1911, 1933 (Box 89)
        - Twin Lakes, 1911 (Box 89)
        - Manhattan, 1926, 1927, 1929 (Box 90)
      - 2 - Xerosere (Box 90)
      - 3 - Succession on Rock
        See: Dendrology File, No. D48G
        See: Dendrology File, No. D47G